<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gluten-free on [::1] YEARL.US</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/gluten-free/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gluten-free on [::1] YEARL.US</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 14:16:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/gluten-free/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-free tortillas (tlaxcali)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-tortillas-tlaxcali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 14:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-tortillas-tlaxcali/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_327&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;695&amp;rdquo;] Tortilladora de madera mezquite[/caption]
Corn (maize) tortillas have to be the quintessential American bread. American as in &amp;lsquo;from the Americas&amp;rsquo;, not &amp;lsquo;USiAn&amp;rsquo;. Several highly organized civilizations flourished in North, Central and South America, all without wheat which was unknown to them. Maize was their staple, and alongside beans, a grass somewhat resembling rice, and potatoes in the South. With these sources of complex carbohydrates who would want for wheat (or barley)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-Free Oat Bread</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-oat-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 15:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-oat-bread/</guid>
      <description>Lest y&amp;rsquo;all think that everything works out in our GF kitchen, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to add that the following did not. Well, not quite. The bread is darned tasty, and is wonderful toasted with a bit of fresh butter. We are BIG butter fans, especially locally made stuff (not Cabots or Land o&#39; Lakes, or anything &amp;lsquo;stick&amp;rsquo; form, really), the sort of butter that is pretty close to tasting of cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-free cornbread (with almond meal)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-cornbread-with-almond-meal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 12:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-cornbread-with-almond-meal/</guid>
      <description>One can&amp;rsquo;t have Thanksgiving without cornbread. This recipe comes as a surprise: I picked up a bag of almond meal whilst shopping and decided to try it as a straight substitute for flour in cornbread. Normally, I use some combination of tapioca flour, garbanzo flour, masa, or any of the other GF powders I have lying around.
With almond meal in hand, I surfed up a couple of recipes, and used this one for inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-free granola</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 17:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-granola/</guid>
      <description>Please, someone, tell me why I did not make granola earlier: for years, I have shied away from purchasing the stuff at the store because it all seems too “fancy” with artificial fruit flavours, etc., that simply do not appeal. What set me to work was seeing “GF granola” on our shopping lists, and realizing just how expensive it is. Really? For what is basically glorified oats? So, I set to; and behold:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-free graham cracker crust</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-graham-cracker-crust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-graham-cracker-crust/</guid>
      <description>When we wanted a gluten-free graham cracker crust for our key lime meringue pie, we looked to Gluten-Free Girl because we wanted a recipe that included the making of graham crackers, rather than a trip to the store for ready-made, GF graham crackers. We followed that recipe pretty closely and came up with crackers that looked like this:

I am often imprecise with measurements, but note them as closely as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lime meringue pie</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/lime-meringue-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 12:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/lime-meringue-pie/</guid>
      <description>We can thank STS-133 for our family&amp;rsquo;s appreciation of key lime pie. While we did see it launch in the end, our first journey to Florida included a trip to the Keys while we waited to hear whether the mission would go ahead. That first trip may end up being the first and last time we sample proper Key Lime Pie, but we&amp;rsquo;ll continue to experiment on our own versions that bring us back to Islamorada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-free beef pasties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-beef-pasties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 18:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-beef-pasties/</guid>
      <description>Gluten-free beef pasties. (This is one where you’ll have to use your own judgment regarding amounts: we just threw it together, but the addition of lamb stock made the filling especially rich. The point of this post? You can be gluten-free and still feed that craving for a pasty.)
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_142&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;225&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Beef fresh from the village butcher&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Filling (ingredients):
  Fresh string beef from the local butcher</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-free Yorkshire pudding</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-yorkshire-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 04:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-yorkshire-pudding/</guid>
      <description>As if a Yorkshire pudding can be gluten-free: please send suggestions of a suitable name for a GF version of something akin to a Yorkshire pudding.
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_133&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;695&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;The pudding, still reasonably puffed up.&amp;quot;][/caption]
Ingredients:
  150 g gluten-free flour[1]
  50 g buckwheat flour
  50 g brown rice flour
  1/2 tsp baking powder
  1/2 tsp xanthan gum
  4 eggs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten free dumplings (x2)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-dumplings-x2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 04:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-dumplings-x2/</guid>
      <description>The first time I tried to make gluten-free dumplings, they worked out beautifully. Indeed, the existence of this blog is largely down to our desire to record those things that go well. For the record: I have not yet replicated those wonderful dumplings, but am working on it.

Cornmeal buckwheat dumplings.
Recipe 1: Cornmeal buckwheat soy dumplings
  1/3 cup (75 g) yellow cornmeal
  1/3 cup (35 g) soy flour</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza with a buckwheat crust</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/pizza-with-a-buckwheat-crust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 06:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/pizza-with-a-buckwheat-crust/</guid>
      <description>Shortly after going gluten-free, we tried Bob&amp;rsquo;s Red Mill gluten-free pizza crust. Having lived in New Haven for many years, we like pizza. Bob&amp;rsquo;s didn&amp;rsquo;t measure up, so that was it&amp;hellip;until now. This might not be apizza, but as long as we&amp;rsquo;re gluten-free we may have to settle for a bit less.

Having found a hit with buckwheat pancakes, I decided to try a buckwheat pizza crust. The recipe I adopted was basically the one described here, but without the garlic powder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buckwheat pancakes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/buckwheat-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 23:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/buckwheat-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>We are big lovers of cornmeal pancakes in our family, but the boys were hankering for something closer to traditional wheat ones, so we figured it was time to throw together a batch of buckwheat pancakes.

Yield: 7 large pancakes
The ingredients:
  1 cup (120 g) buckwheat flour
  ½ cup (20 g) masa harina
  ¼ tsp. baking soda
  2/3 tsp. baking powder</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-free naan bread?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-naan-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 12:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-naan-bread/</guid>
      <description>There is a chicken curry bubbling on the stove, saffron rice steaming away in the rice cooker: how can I not think of naan bread?

I surfed up a recipe for gluten-free naan bread, and this is what I found: http://www.food.com/recipe/gluten-free-naan-roti-indian-flat-bread-version-1-189334
I spent less than 30 minutes from start to finish, and in the end we had 2 large and 3 smaller naan breads.The final recipe looked like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluten-free Christmas pudding</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-christmas-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 17:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gluten-free-christmas-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Even though this is our first gluten-free Christmas, we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to miss out on the pudding. So, we made our own. I was apprehensive, but need not have been.

The basic recipe I followed was this one. Note that you have to scroll down the page quite a ways to actually reach the recipe.
I also had this one on hand and my final result combined aspects of both and may have included some improvisation re: dried fruits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craving a mince pie but you&#39;re following a gluten-free diet?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/craving-a-mince-pie-but-youre-following-a-gluten-free-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/craving-a-mince-pie-but-youre-following-a-gluten-free-diet/</guid>
      <description>How did we do it? First of all, I picked up a new kitchen scale. It&amp;rsquo;s digital and switches easily between metric and US standard units. This makes it easy to fool around with different types of gluten-free flour since the only thing that really matters is that there be double the mass of flour to fat.
Right. What about those pies?
  Cranberry mince pies. For the filling, I pretty much followed the recipe given here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
