<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on [::1] yearl.us</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on [::1] yearl.us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:01:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Posting from IA Writer to Wordpress (Coleman)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posting-from-ia-writer-to-wordpress-coleman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posting-from-ia-writer-to-wordpress-coleman/</guid>
      <description>IA Writer to Wordpress 0. Wha? With the coming of the new doggie into the house, perhaps I will again add more content to the bloggy thing that I have kinda sorta not really been keeping over the last little while.
Probably this has been done by someone else on the Intertubz, but ach, why not. I have some time on my hands, so here are running notes in IA Writer that will make its way to a Wordpress post by some means or other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>74111101&#39;s The Universe questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/74111101s-the-universe-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 14:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/74111101s-the-universe-questions/</guid>
      <description>74111101&amp;ndash; yes, my eldest insists on representing himself as the ASCII decimal code point values for his name&amp;ndash; and I have been watching the History Channel&amp;rsquo;s The Universe. Below some of 74&amp;rsquo;s questions (typed verbatim from his notes) that he hopes to have answered after writing to some of the presenters in the series.
Questions   If the Universe keeps on expanding will it eventually rip apart the things that make up dark energy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Posterous to Wordpress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/from-posterous-to-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 21:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/from-posterous-to-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>The not-very-much-used-by-me Posterous is going offline on April 30th 2013, roughly 12 months after its acquisition by Twitter. I had a few on-and-off posts there, and I guess it would sort of be a shame to loose them, so this is an attempted replacement. The Posterous blog is copied here: http://sjy.yearl.us/sjy/posterous/blog.yearl.us/ &amp;hellip; that was a simple [ccI_bash]wget -r -l inf -k -E -p -nc blog.yearl.us [/cc] but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d also try and group these pages into Wordpress itself a lá http://en.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 14:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Fsked the http://mary.yearl.us WP install last night whilst arsing with names. One single bloody typo in &amp;ldquo;site URL&amp;rdquo; and good luck getting back into the admin panel. WP does not even offer a warning that changing this might be a bad thing, or potentially so.
Fortunately having access to the database I could edit the value in-place in the tables&amp;hellip; now all is well again with the world.
&amp;hellip;except for the fact that I felt I had to sign up&amp;ndash;finally&amp;ndash; for a twitter account just so I could get an API key in order to explore some things on Mar&amp;rsquo;s blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
